  Full console.error → logInfraError retrofit

  The infra-logger system is already in place at src/errors/infra-logger.ts, exported from
  src/errors/index.ts as logInfraError(label: string, err: unknown): void. It logs to console.error
  internally and calls errorHandler.incrementErrorCount. The goal is to retrofit all bare
  console.error calls inside catch blocks to use logInfraError so errors get telemetry counting.

  Scope: src/, shared/, ui/ — .ts, .tsx, .js, .jsx
  Exclude: node_modules/, dist/, build/, *.test.ts, *.spec.ts, __tests__/

  Import path by location:
  - File in src/execution/pipeline/ → import { logInfraError } from '../../errors';
  - File in src/provenance/ → import { logInfraError } from '../errors';
  - File in ui/hooks/chat/ → import { logInfraError } from '../../../src/errors';
  - File in ui/shell/layout/ → import { logInfraError } from '../../../src/errors';
  - File in shared/ → import { logInfraError } from '../src/errors';
  - General rule: resolve src/errors relative to the file's location. Never use absolute paths.
  - If logInfraError is already imported in the file, do not add a duplicate import.

  ---
  What to change

  Before:
  } catch (err) {
    console.error('[some/label] operation failed:', err);
  }

  After:
  } catch (err) {
    logInfraError('some/label', err);
  }

  The label comes from the existing console.error string — strip the brackets and trailing message,
  keep the path. If the existing label is vague (e.g. [Error]), derive a specific one from the file
  path and function name: module/functionName.

  ---
  Hard skip rules — do not touch these

  1. Provider/concierge error handlers — any catch inside src/providers/ or src/concierge-service/
  that calls errorHandler.handleProviderError, errorHandler.handleError, normalizeError, or
  handleProviderError directly. These already increment the counter internally; retrofitting would
  double-count.
  2. Already uses logInfraError — skip entirely, no changes needed.
  3. console.warn catches — do not touch. console.warn is used for documented expected conditions
  (Chrome port closed on navigation, clipboard permission denied, WebGPU unavailable, feature
  detection fallbacks). These must stay as console.warn. Do not upgrade them to logInfraError.
  4. Catches that rethrow — if the catch body is console.error(...); throw err; — retrofit is fine,
  the rethrow stays identical.
  5. Catches that call multiple loggers — if the catch already calls both console.error and something
  else (e.g. persistenceMonitor.recordError, setAlertText), replace only the console.error line with
  logInfraError. Leave all other lines untouched.
  6. The errors module itself — skip src/errors/ entirely.
  7. JS files without module imports — files like src/offscreen/embedding-controller.js that have no
  ES module imports cannot import logInfraError. Use console.error directly in those files. Do not add
   an import statement to a non-module JS file.
  8. console.error outside catch blocks — only retrofit console.error calls that are directly inside a
   catch body. Do not touch console.error calls in normal code paths, .catch() chains on
  fire-and-forget promises where the error is not the catch variable, or error boundary render
  methods.
  9. .catch(() => console.error(...)) inline lambdas — these are fine to retrofit to .catch((err) => {
   logInfraError('label', err); }). But only if the .catch is on a fire-and-forget call (not one where
   the return value is used or the error is re-thrown upstream).
  10. Do not rename catch variables unless the existing name is _ or _e with no references in the
  body. If the body references e, keep e. If the body references err, keep err.
  11. Do not change indentation, braces, or control flow. The only lines that change are the
  console.error(...) call and the import block.
  12. Preserve the original diagnostic content exactly. If the existing console.error message
  contains interpolated values, contextual strings, or multi-part arguments, carry them into
  the label or as additional output alongside logInfraError. Do not discard any information
  that was present in the original call.

  ---
  Execution order

  Process one directory at a time. After each directory, run npm run typecheck, report the result, and
   stop for human approval before moving to the next.

  1. src/execution/
  2. src/provenance/
  3. src/geometry/
  4. src/clustering/
  5. src/shadow/
  6. src/system/
  7. src/sw-entry.ts
  8. src/persistence/
  9. src/providers/ — skip catches already using provider error handlers
  10. src/concierge-service/ — same rule
  11. shared/
  12. ui/state/
  13. ui/hooks/
  14. ui/instrument/
  15. ui/reading/
  16. ui/shell/
  17. ui/chat/
  18. ui/services/
  19. ui/shared/
  20. ui/utils/
  21. Anything remaining under ui/ not yet covered
