## Mission

Audit the codebase for `catch` blocks and `.catch()` handlers that silently swallow errors, and add `console.error` logging so they surface in the browser devtools console. **This must not change runtime behavior.** Every existing return value, default fallback, and control-flow path stays identical. The pipeline behaves exactly as it does today — operators just gain visibility into errors that are currently invisible.

This codebase is in active production. Silent swallows accumulated during the JS→TS conversion when `catch (e)` became `catch (e: unknown)` and previous agents "fixed" type errors by deleting the log instead of properly typing it. The goal is to restore visibility without altering recovery behavior.

## Scope

**Include:** `src/`, `ui/`, `shared/`, `offscreen/`
**Exclude:** `node_modules/`, `dist/`, `build/`, `.codesight/`, any `*.test.ts`, `*.spec.ts`, `__tests__/`
**Languages:** `.ts`, `.tsx`, `.js`, `.jsx`

## Patterns to find

Use the Grep tool with these regexes. Inspect every match.

1. **Empty / no-op catches:**
   ```
   catch\s*\([^)]*\)\s*\{\s*\}
   catch\s*\{\s*\}
   ```

2. **Silent return-only catches** (no log, just returns a default — these are the most common case):
   ```
   catch\s*\([^)]*\)\s*\{\s*return\b
   ```

3. **Promise `.catch` silencers:**
   ```
   \.catch\s*\(\s*\(\s*\)\s*=>\s*(null|undefined|\{\}|void\s+0|false|true)\s*\)
   \.catch\s*\(\s*\([^)]*\)\s*=>\s*(null|undefined|\{\}|void\s+0|false|true)\s*\)
   ```

4. **`void e;` or bare-identifier catches:**
   ```
   catch\s*\([^)]+\)\s*\{\s*(void\s+\w+;?\s*|\w+;\s*)\}
   ```

5. **Comments flagging intentional swallow** (review for legitimacy, may need a `console.warn`):
   ```
   //\s*(ignore|swallow|suppress|silent|noop|no-op)
   ```

For each match, read enough surrounding context (the function body, ideally) to understand:
- What operation was being attempted
- What the recovery value/path is
- Whether the swallow is intentional (rare — usually feature detection)

## Canonical fix pattern

### Before (silent swallow):
```ts
try {
  const data = await fetchSomething(id);
  return data;
} catch (e) {
  return null;
}
```

### After (additive log, behavior unchanged):
```ts
try {
  const data = await fetchSomething(id);
  return data;
} catch (err) {
  console.error('[module-name/functionName] fetchSomething failed:', err);
  return null;
}
```

### Promise chain — Before:
```ts
loadConfig().catch(() => DEFAULT_CONFIG);
```

### Promise chain — After:
```ts
loadConfig().catch((err) => {
  console.error('[module-name/loadConfig] failed, using DEFAULT_CONFIG:', err);
  return DEFAULT_CONFIG;
});
```

### Label format

`[<module-or-short-file>/<function-or-context>] <one-line description>:`

Examples:
- `[session-manager/_attachRunIdMeta] failed to read inflight metadata:`
- `[mapping-phase/runMapping] paragraph projection failed, continuing without it:`
- `[shadow-extractor/extractStatements] regex parse failed for response:`

Labels should be short but greppable. The reader scanning a noisy console must be able to identify the source quickly.

### Severity choice

- **`console.error`** — default. Use whenever an unexpected exception was caught. Even if the recovery is graceful, the underlying failure is unexpected.
- **`console.warn`** — use only when the catch is genuinely an *expected* condition (e.g., feature detection, "this API may not exist in some contexts"). Must be justified in code by an adjacent comment.
- **`console.info`** / **`console.log`** — never, for caught errors.

## Hard rules — what NOT to change

1. **Do not add new try/catch blocks.** Only modify existing ones.
2. **Do not move code into or out of try blocks.** The architectural question of "should geometry be inside the try block in mapping-phase" is out of scope for this task. Don't touch it.
3. **Do not rethrow where the code currently swallows.** Adding `throw err` after the log changes behavior — forbidden.
4. **Do not change return values, default fallbacks, or recovery branches.** If the catch returned `null`, it still returns `null` after.
5. **Do not consolidate or remove existing logs.** If a catch already calls `console.error`, leave it. If it already calls a project logger like `getSessionLogger().error`, leave it. Only *add* where missing.
6. **Do not rename catch variables across-the-board.** If the existing variable name (`e`, `err`, `error`) is referenced inside the catch body, keep it. Only rename when adopting `err` doesn't break a reference.
7. **Do not touch test files** even if they match patterns.
8. **Do not "improve" the error message by reading `err.message`** unless you also write a type guard (`err instanceof Error ? err.message : String(err)`). The simpler `console.error('[...] :', err)` form prints the full Error object including stack — preferred.

## Special cases — leave alone

- **Already logging:** catches that call `console.*`, `logger.*`, `getSessionLogger().*`, or any project-specific log function. Skip.
- **Already rethrowing:** catches whose entire body is `throw err` or equivalent. The rethrow is the surfacing mechanism. Skip.
- **Documented intentional swallow:** catches with an adjacent comment explaining why silence is correct (e.g., `// chrome.tabs may not exist in offscreen context`). For these, *upgrade* to `console.warn` (one-time visibility into the expected condition is still useful for debugging) **only if** the comment confirms intent. Otherwise treat as silent and apply `console.error`.
- **Pure type-narrowing catches:** catches whose only purpose is to narrow a type at a boundary, with no recovery behavior. Rare. If found, treat as silent and add `console.error`.

## Execution order

Process directories in this order so the diff stays reviewable and high-blast-radius shared code is fixed first:

1. `shared/`
2. `src/persistence/`
3. `src/execution/`
4. `src/provenance/`, `src/geometry/`, `src/clustering/`, `src/shadow/`
5. `src/system/`, `src/sw-entry.ts`, `src/offscreen/`, `src/providers/`, `src/concierge-service/`
6. `ui/state/`, `ui/services/`, `ui/hooks/`
7. `ui/chat/`, `ui/instrument/`, `ui/reading/`, `ui/shell/`, `ui/components/`
8. Anything else under `ui/` not yet covered

After each directory, run typecheck (`npm run build` or whatever the project uses — check `package.json` `scripts`) before moving on. If typecheck fails, fix only the new failure introduced by your edits — do not fix unrelated pre-existing errors.

## Verification (after all directories complete)

1. **Typecheck passes:** `npm run build` (or equivalent). No new errors.
2. **Tests pass:** any existing test suite. No new failures.
3. **Diff is purely additive:** review the full diff. Every change should be either:
   - A new `console.error` / `console.warn` line inside an existing catch body, OR
   - A safe `(e)` → `(err)` rename inside a single catch where no other reference uses the old name.
   No deletions of code, no reordering, no moved braces, no changed return values.

If the diff contains anything else, revert that hunk.

## Final report

Produce a markdown summary at the end:

```
# Silent Error Surfacing — Audit Report

## Totals
- Catches audited: N
- Catches updated (added console.error/warn): N
- Already logging — skipped: N
- Intentional swallow — left alone: N (with reasons)
- Files touched: N

## Updated catches by directory
- shared/: N catches across M files
- src/persistence/: ...
- (etc)

## Intentional swallows preserved
- path/to/file.ts:LINE — reason from comment
- (etc)

## Notes / things worth flagging
- (anything that looked suspicious but didn't match the rules — e.g. catches that swallow but the recovery value seems wrong; flag for human review, do not fix)
```

---

## Operator-side: how to read the new logs

After this lands, every silent failure will print to the devtools console with a `[module/function]` prefix. To monitor in production:

- Open devtools on the extension's service worker (chrome://extensions → "service worker" link)
- Open devtools on the UI page
- Open devtools on the offscreen document (chrome://extensions → "offscreen" link, if available)
- Filter by `[` prefix or specific module name when investigating a report

Errors will not block the pipeline. They surface so you can investigate.